Guide to the Brooklyn letterhead collection BCMS.0008
Brooklyn Collection
- Dugan, A., 1879, 1882
  Wood mouldings/Moulding mill. Junction of Classon and Kent Avenues
- Dugan Brothers, Inc., 1929-1930
  Bakers. 288 South 5th Street
- Dumbleton, Wm. & Sons, 1883
  Masons and builders. 578 Carlton Avenue
- Dunbar Cane Products Corporation, 1924
  Molasses and syrup. 228-236 King Street
- Duncan, John C. & Son / John C. Duncan's Son, 1886, 1895
  Hardware and house furnishing goods and builders' supplies. 1768 Fulton Street
- Dunlap & Co., 1891
  178 & 180 Fifth Ave.
- Dunn, Joseph F., 1896, 1898
  Carpenter and builder. 478, 503 Court Street
- Dunn, P. & L., 1895-1897
  Plumbers, gas and steam fitters. 454 Gates Avenue
- Dunne, Chas. J., 1898
  Meats and poultry. 761 Flatbush Ave. near Clarkson St.
- Dunne, Desmond Co., 1896
  Advertising. Eagle building
- Dunnigan, James A., 1897
  Roofing. 478 Court Street
- Durand & McCloskey, 1888
  Frame maker and gilders. 509 Myrtle Ave., near Grand
- Dureimurs, J.C. & Co., 1888, 1890
  Painters and paper hangers. 18 Rochester Avenue
- Durkee & Hough, 1863
  Storage and commission merchants. 94 Pearl Street
- Durkee, J.W. and Co., 1897
  Manufacturers of sauces. 49 & 51 Hall St.
- Durring Brothers, 1891
  Upholsterers and manufacturers of cabinets. 944 & 946 Fulton St.
- Durro Process Printing Company, 1954
  Thermographers. 969 Broadway
- Dutcher, D.P., 1890
  Real estate and insurance. 79th St. & 5th Ave.
- Dutton, John S., 1904
  Plumber and gas fitter. 931 DeKalb Avenue
- Dyas, Saml. & Co., 1868
  Booksellers and stationers. 246 Fulton St.
- Dykeman, James H., 1880, 1883
  Packing box factory, re-sawing and planing mills. 507, 501-511 Union Street
- Eadie, James C., 1886
  Auctioneer and real estate broker. 45 Broadway
- Eagle Hotel, 1892
  254-258 Fulton Street
- Eagle Iron Works, 1924
  850 DeKalb Avenue
- Eagle Printing, 1944
  Printer. 379 Sutter Avenue
- Eakin, H.E., 1863, 1870
  Roofer. Corner Orange and Henry Streets, near Fulton
- Earle, S.A. & Co., 1886
  Plumbers and gas fitters. 1039 Fulton Street
- Early & McKeon, 1868, 1869, 1874
  Stoves, ranges, furnaces etc.. 501 Columbia St., bet. Union and President Sts.; 257 Columbia Street, between President and Carroll Sts.
- East Brooklyn Painting Establishment, 1888-1889
  Painting and paper hanging. 483 DeKalb Ave. [formerly 261 Franklin Ave.]
- East Brooklyn Savings and Loan Association, 1962
  1012 Gates Avenue
- East Brooklyn Savings Bank, 1881, 1886
- East New York Furniture Co., 1892
  Furniture. Corner Atlantic and Pennsylvania Avenues
- East New York Lanterns, 1894
  Lanterns. Corner Fulton and Sheffield Avenues
- Eastern Fire Proof Sash & Door Co., 1926
  Maker of fire proof doors. Office, 826 Flushing Ave.; Factory, 10-12 Beaver St.
- Eastman, F.M., 1888-1889
  Insurance. 155, 168 Montague St. cor. Clinton
- Eastmans Company of New York, 1893
  Butcher. 96 East Avenue
- Easton, Sarah E., 1889
  Dock building materials. Cor. Hamilton Ave. and Clinton St.
- Eayrs, J.W., 1879
  Ships' cabooses. 10 Columbia St.
- Ecker & Morehouse, 1880
  Real estate and insurance. 916 Gates Avenue
- Eckert, Charles A., 1872
  Liquor Store. 123 Atlantic Street
- Eckhart, John H., 1899
  Bicycle maker. 901 Flatbush Avenue
- Eddy, Elias T., 1882
  Window and door manufacturer. 221 and 223 North Second Street
- Eddy, Geo. M. & Co., 1899-1900
  Tape measure manufacturer. 345 to 353 Classon Avenue
- Eddy, William, 1910
  Shipwright. Marine Yacht Basin, Ulmer Park
- Edison Electric Illuminating Company of Brooklyn, 1909
  Electric company. 360 Pearl Street
- Edmiston & Waddell, 1885
  Farm machine maker. 351 & 353 First Street
- Edmonds, Kirby & Co., 1863-1864
  Coal and wood dealer. Yard, Wall St. Ferry; Office, 20 Fulton St.
- Edwards, Alexander, 1864-1867
  Granite dealer. Yards at Sedgwick St. near Hamilton Ferry and cor. of 5th Avenue and 25th St., Greenwood
- Edwards, F., 1876, 1878
  Shoemaker. 166 & 168 Atlantic Ave.
- Edwards, J. & Co., 1878
  Tin and sheet iron ware. 608 Atlantic Ave.
- Edwards, John, 1854, 1866
  Dealer in marble and granite, stone cutter. (Near) Greenwood Cemetery
- Edwards, Jos., 1883, 1884, 1892
  Metal worker. 101 Flatbush Avenue
- Egan, Thomas, 1892
  Coal and wood dealer. Yards, 928 Bedford Ave. cor. Willoughby and 96 Grand Ave. near Myrtle
- Egan, Thomas E., 1897
  Carpenter and builder. 11th St. and 5th Ave.
- Eggert, Chas. H. & Bro., 1896
  Manufacturers of cigars. 1512 & 1514 Atlantic Avenue
- Ehlers, Albert, Inc., 1929, 1933
  Tea, coffee and spices. 1300 Flushing Avenue
- Einhorn Bros., 1943
  Typewriter dealer and renter. 1424 Mermaid Avenue
- Elflein, Fred'k & Sons, 1917
  Confectionery, drusgtore and bakery. 216-226 Seigel Street
- Elford, George (& Son), 1867, 1889
  Painter and paper hanger. 160, 506 Fulton Ave., betw. Bond St. and Hanover Place
- Ellery & Garrison, 1880, 1881, 1889
  Painters. Formerly Ellery, Garrison & Co. 520 DeKalb Avenue
- Ellis, J.W., 1890
  Roofer. Nos. 459 to 461 Flushing Ave.
- Ellis, Uriah, 1883
  Plumber and gas fitter. 949 Broadway, near DeKalb Avenue
- Elsesser, Michael, 1910
  Machinist and blacksmith. Foot of Court Street
- Elsinger, Daniel, 1888
  Blacksmith. 61 Ann Street
- Elwood, The, 1891
  Hotel [?]. 62, 64, & 66 Livingston St.
- Emmerich, Fred, 1886, 1888
  Machinist and locksmith. 696 Myrtle Avenue; 386 Bedford Ave., near Myrtle
- Empire Biscuit Comopany, The, 1902
  Biscuit makers. Wallabout Market
- Empire Line, 1891
  Railroad. Station, foot of North Fourth Street
- Empire State Dairy Co., 1915
  Dairy. 496 to 506 Broadway
- Empire State Surety Company, The, 1906
  Bonds. 391 Fulton Street
- Enderby & Dalton, 1865, 1867
  Plumbers and gas fitters. 122 Broadway (late South 7th Street), bet. 4th & 5th Sts.
- Enderby, Henry, 1886
  Plumber and gas fitter. 95 South 6th St.
- Engelhardt, Philipp, 1871
  Carpenter and builder. 14 Fayette Street, near corner of Broadway & Flushing Ave.
- Engelhardt, Th., 1891
  Architect. 905 Broadway, cor. Wall Street
- English, German & French Day School, 1888
  154 Montague Street
- Ennis, John, 1918
  Shoe maker. 790 Grand Street
- Enrico Caruso Museum of America Inc., The, 1996
  Museum. 1942 East 19th Street
- Enterprise Cement Roofing Co., 1866
  Roofer. 2 Court Street and 59 Fulton Street
- Erb, Charles, 1890
  Painter and paper hanger. 318 & 320 Wythe Ave., near Grand St.
- Ericson & Ericson
  Undertaker. 535 Atlantic Avenue bet. 3rd & 4th Aves.
- Ericson & Osterberg, 1896
  Painters and decorators. 335 Second Street/253 Flatbush Ave.
- Ernst, F.A., 1865
  Clothing/tailor. 224 Court Street
- Ernst, Henry, 1881
  Sign painter. 698 Myrtle Avenue
- Ertrachter, Samuel, 1913
  Painting, deocrating, general contracting. 69 Court Street
- Eskin, I., 1943
  Hardware supplies. 2424 Mermaid Avenue
- Esperson, William E., 1889
  Tin and iron worker. 143 Clermont Avenue
- Essig, George, 1894
  Druggist and apothecary. Bedford Ave., corner Division
- Estey Wire Works Company, 1907
  Wirecloth Maker. 65 Fulton Street
- Euclid School, 1926
  School. Fulton Street and Nostrand Avenue
- Eureka Glass Works, 1888
  Glassmaker. 263 Gold St., bet. Concord & Tillary
- Evans, N. & Son, 1882
  Real estate and insurance. 391 Bedford Ave., near Myrtle; 681 Myrtle Ave.
- Evans, W.M., 1899
  Dairy. 250 Hewes St.
- Everett, Chas., 1899
  Mason. 845 Bedford Ave., near Myrtle
- Evergreen Board of Trade, 1912
  Board of trade. meetings held at 63 Washington Avenue
- Evergreens Cemetery, The, 1894, 1938
  Principal entrance Bushwick Ave. & Conway St.
- Excelsior Brewing Co., The, 1923
  227-277 Pulaski Street; office 254 Hart Street
- Excelsior Glass Co., 1899-1900
  Glass dealer. 6 and 8 Union Ave.
- Excelsior Lantern Company, 1870
  Lantern makers. 240-244 Plymouth Street
- Excelsior Wire Ware-house, 1869
  Wire makers. 43 Fulton St.
- Ex-Lax Company, The, 1931
  Medicine makers
- Fagan, John, 1869
  Stable and carriage rentals. SW cor. of Hicks and Harrison Streets
- Fager, Edward, 1888-1889
  Locksmith and bell hanger. 696 Myrtle Avenue
- Fairchild, F.M. and Sons, 1909
  Funeral directors. 158 Reid Ave., 702 Fulton St.
- Fairchild Sons Inc., 1940
  Morticians. 86 Lefferts Place
- Fallon, Martin, 1879, 1887, 1896
  Plumber and gas fitter. 12, 53 DeKalb Avenue
- Fancher & Valentine, 1873
  Wagon and carriage maker. India Street, near Franklin
- Farber, H.J., 1903
  Painter and decorator
- Farmers & Citizens National Bank, 1860
- Farmers Feed Company, 1937
  Feed dealer. Johnson Ave. & Bogart St.
- Farnworth, George, 1881, 1885-1887
  Painter and decorator, paper hanger. 1667-1/2 Fulton Ave., opp. Schenectady Ave.
- Farragut Fire Insurance Co., 1888
  81 Broadway
- Farrell Auto Company, 1925
  Auto dealer. 1125 Atlantic Avenue at Bedford Avenue
- Farrell, Peter, 1894
  Livery stable. 106 Third Avenue
- Farrington & Messick, 1890
  Bed and mattress maker. 33 Powers Street
- Fassnacht, G., 1896
  Painter and paper hanger. 1856 Fulton Street, opp. Patchen Avenue
- Faupel, Fred C., 1941
  Real estate. 1209 Flatbush Ave. at Ditmas Ave., 549 E. 26th St. at Flatbush Ave.
- Fehleison Brothers, 1882
  Butcher. 424 Classon Ave. near Gates
- Feinberg, A., 1925
  Burnt leather novelties. 2377 Pitkin Avenue
- Fellows, John, 1888
  Hardware. 70 Broadway
- Female Employment Society, 1861
  Clothing and sewing. 65 Court Street
- Ferguson, A. & C., 1897
  Feed dealer. 40 Grand Street
- Ferguson, R., 1882
  Mason and builder
- Ferguson, Robert B., 1874
  Carpenter and builder. 235 Ainslie Street near Graham Avenue
- Ferrall,John & Son, 1864, 1866
  Distillers. 10 Water Street
- Field, Frank S., 1889
  Art supplies. 457 Fulton Street
- Field, George, 1861
  Notary public. Cor. of South 7th & 1st Sts.
- Fillmore Lumber Co., 1941
  Lumber merchant. 2286 Flatbush Avenue
- Finch, Fred J., 1884, 1887
  Shoe store. 485 Fulton Street, bet. Bridge & Lawrence
- Finckenauer Bros., 1900
  Undertakers. 155 Bridge St., bet. Sands and High Sts.
- Finkensieper, Paul, 1905
  Plumber and gas fitter. 58 Reid Avenue, cor. Lafayette Ave.
- Finn Brothers, 1901
  Office furniture maker. Factory, 82-88 Schermerhorn St.
- Fio Bros
  Auto collision service. 286 North 8th Street
- Fireman's Trust Insurance Company of Brooklyn, 1864, 1866, 1870, 1871, 1875, 1876, 1880
  9, 26 Court St.; 201 Montague Street
- Fireside Fuels, Inc., 1940
  Fuel dealer. 870 East 42nd Street
- First Assembly District Democratic Association, 1930
  Political association. 350 Atlantic Avenue
- First National Bank, 1870
  Formerly Farmers and Citizens National Bank.
- First Reformed Dutch Church, 1869, 1871
- Fishbane, Myron, 1993
  Accountant. 8700 25th Avenue
- Fisher, James A., 1881, 1883
  Real estate and insurance. 1415 Fulton Avenue
- Fitkin, Thos. F., 1872, 1876, 1883
  Saddle and harness maker. 38 Broadway
- Fitter, C. & Son, 1891
  Dairy. 11 Wallabout Market
- Fitz, Philip G., 1947
  Attorney. 1479 Flatbush Avenue
- Fitzgerald, E.C.M., 1915
  Laundry and clothing repair. 44 Court Street
- Fitzgerald, Henry & Co., 1889
  Grocer. 20 Washington Ave.
- Fitzpatrick, William J., 1892
  Plumber and gas fitter. 449 and 451 Fifth Avenue
- Flaherty, John J., 1890, 1895
  Plumber and gas fitter. 382 Seventh Avenue
- Flatbush Gas Company, The, 1911
  Gas supplier. 1034 and 1036 Flatbush Avenue
- Flatbush Novelty Corp., 1967
  General merchandise. 2206 Flatbush Ave.
- Flatbush Observer, Inc., The, 1936
  Publisher. 1516-1518 Flatbush Avenue
- Flatbush Real Estate Board, Inc., 1950, 1955
  1479 Flatbush Avenue
- Flatbush Reformed Church, 1939
- Flatbush, Town of, The, 1864
- Flatbush Toy Company, 1940
  Toy makers. 1181 Flatbush Avenue
- Flatbush Zionist Organization, 1960
  1625 Ocean Avenue
- Flatlands Glass & Shade Co., 1937
  Glass and shade dealer. 2051 Flatbush Avenue
- Fleer Bros. Inc. Fuel, 1922
  Fuel dealers. 281-291 Tompkins Ave., 416-422 Lexington Ave.
- Fleig, Beatus, 1865
  Night work. 108 Boerum St., between Ewen St. & Graham Avenue
- Fleischmann, John H., 1891
  Printer. 128 & 130 Meserole Street
- Fleischman, M., 1893
  Plumber and gas fitter. 543 Marcy Ave. [formerly 77 Hamburg Ave.]
- Fletcher, A.W., 1907
  Furnaces, heaters, and metal work. 918 Myrtle Avenue
- Fletcher, Horace R., 1884
  Real estate. 365 Flatbush Avenue
- Flickenschild, P.C.A., 1904
  Grocer. 400 Crescent Street, cor. Hill Street
- Flood, John W., 1898-1899
  Horseshoer. Tulip Street/Rutland Road, bet. Brooklyn and New York Aves.
- Flower, J.H., 1879, 1881, 1888
  Hat and cane dealer. 441 Fulton St.
- Flynn, J., 1897
  Carpenter and builder. 387 Douglass Street
- Flynn, John, 1870
  Liquor dealers. 221 Myrtle Avenue, near Navy Street
- Folk, J.M., 1870
  Carpenter and builder. 203 Nassau Street
- Folk & Yeomans, 1872
  Carpenter and builder. 173 Clymer St.
- Foran, Thomas, 1876
  Grocer. 481 Court St., cor. of Nelson
- Forbell Plumbing Supply Co., Inc., 1932
  Plumbing supplier. 1226 Liberty Ave.
- Force & Kentana, 1893
  Butcher. 192 Fort Greene Place
- Ford, N. & Son, 1871
  Stable. 181-187 Union Street
- Forman, Ed., 1886
  Plaster ornament maker. 735 Gates Avenue
- Forman, Jas., 1884
  Iron and wire work. 129 Court St.
- Forsbrey, 1881
  Plumber and gas fitter. 698 DeKalb Avenue
- Forster, Frank J., 1900
  Cigar maker. 258 Graham Avenue
- Foster Brothers, 1871
  Carpet dealer. 257 Fulton Street
- Fourteenth Infantry, 1927
- Fourteenth Infantry Post, The Fighting, 1930
  1402 Eighth Avenue
- Fourteenth Regiment Camp No. 14, 1927
  8th Avenue and 15th Street
- Fox, Edward J., 1880
  China and glass dealer. 139 Court St., corner of Atlantic
- Fox, H.M., 1883
  Baker. 1085 Fulton Avenue
- Fox, John, 1905
  Metal worker and roofer. 323 Putnam Ave.
- Fox, Peter, 1883
  Painter and paper hanger. 870 Fulton Street, near Clinton Ave.
- Fox, P.J., 1888
  Copper smith and plumbing. 66 Hudson Ave., near Water St.
- Fox & Rain [formerly Alex. Rain], 1896
  Constable and notary public. NW cor. State and Court Sts.
- Fraas, John, 1899
  Furniture makers. 5-11 Cook St., near Broadway
- Frank, Samuel C., Dr., 1925
  Optometrist. 1592 Pitkin Avenue
- Franke, Arthur Realty, 1967
  Real estate and insurance. 1479 Flatbush Avenue, at Glenwood Road
- Frankel, B., 1895
  Glass dealer. 695 Third Avenue bet. 21st and 22nd St.
- Frankel, J., 1889
  Glass dealer. 26 Myrtle Ave. [formerly 426 Flushing Ave.]
- Franklin Fire Insurance Company
  Insurance. 215 Montague Street
- Franze & Johnson, 1881
  Painters. 239 Court Street
- Frauenstein, L., 1888
  Housewares. 543 Grand Street, near Graham Avenue
- Frazer, Alex, 1879
  Shoe store. 1367 Fulton Street
- Frazier, John, 1865
  Roofer. 18 Water Street, near Fulton Ferry
- Frazier, S.R., 1871
  Lumber dealer. Cor. Bridge & Plymouth Streets
- Freda Laboratories, 1950
  Medical laboratory. 20 Seventh Avenue
- Frederick, S.R., 1929
  Painter, plasterer, and decorator. 6007 Fifth Avenue
- Fredsall, S.A., 1890
  Upholsterer. 756 Fulton Street, cor. Carlton Ave.
- Freeland, William, 1883
  Wagon and carriage maker. 291 Bedford Avenue, near Flushing Ave.
- Freisem, George C., 1918
  Bakers' supplies. 42 Washington Ave.
- French Cabinet Corporation, 1919
  Cabinet makers. Metropolitan and Flushing Aves.
- French, H.B., 1876
  Blacksmith. 112 Grand Street
- George Frentzel, 1899
  Printer. 76 Bartlett Street, near Broadway
- Friedlander, J., 1914
  Plumber. 2106 Atlantic Avenue
- Friedlander, J., 1914
  Plumber and tinsmith. 277 Saratoga Avenue
- Friedman-Doscher Co., The, 1898
  Soap makers. 485 to 495 Kent Avenue [formerly Raymond cor. Boliver St.]
- Friedman, Henry, 1915
  Roofers. 1403 Myrtle Avenue, near Harman St.
- Friedrick, Alphonse, 1882
  Stained glass works. 16 and 18 Hoyt Street, near Fulton Ave.
- Friel, Daniel, 1869
  Carriage makers. 19 Hicks Street, near Fulton
- Frith, Francis E., 1892
  Coal dealer. 31 to 47 Schenk Str.
- Frutkoff, S.F., 1913
  Glass dealer. 1893 Fulton Street
- Fry & Lyle, 1886
  Real estate. 1550 Fulton Street
- Fuhry, J., 1877
  Hat dealer. 576 Fulton Street, near Navy Street
- Fulton Bag & Cotton Mills, 1917
  Bag maker. 330 Wythe Ave.
- Fulton, David, 1879
  Metal worker. 507 DeKalb Ave., bet. Skillman St. & Franklin Ave.
- Fulton, David, 1880, 1882
  Hardware, house furnishings, and heaters. 519 DeKalb Ave.
- Fulton Lumber Co., The, 1927
  Lumber dealer. 1534 Fulton Street
- Fulton Municipal Gas Co. of Brooklyn, The, 1894
  Gas supplier. 44 Court St.
- Fulton Service Corporation, 1947
  Property management, mortgages and insurance. 32 Court Street
- Funck, Charles, 1892
  Painter and decorator. 177 Division Ave.
- Funk Brothers, 1895-1896
  Oil dealers. Grand St. and Newtown Creek
- Furnas, O.A., 1886
  Carpenter. 250 Baltic Street
- G. & R. Furniture Co., 1928
  Furniture. 5815-17-19 Fifth Avenue
- Gabb, George('s Sons), 1879, 1880, 1889
  Painters. 179 Atlantic Street; 99 Atlantic Avenue
- Gabel, R., 1938
  Carpet dealer. 484 Rockaway Avenue
- Gabriel, J .& C., 1890
  Heaters and house furnishings. 506 Grand Street
- Gaetjens, Berger & Wirth Inc., 1935
  Ink dealer. 60 Columbia Heights
- Gaff & Nattrass, 1884
  Plumbers, steam and gas fitters. 694 Fulton Street and 115 Portland Avenue
- Gagliano, S., 1925
  Real estate and insurance. 12 Stone Avenue
- Gair, Robert, 1897, 1900
  Paper dealers and printers. General office: Washington, Water, and Plymouth Streets; Factory, Brooklyn [Dumbo?]
- Galbally, John, 1888-1889
  Painter and decorator. 143 Park Ave., near Cumberland Street
- Galbally, Wm., 1887, 1889
  Plumber, steam and gas fitter. 138 Park Avenue, near Carlton
- Gallagher, Alfred A., 1888
  Insurance. 424 Bedford Avenue, near South 8th Street
- Gallagher, Felix, 1866, 1870
  Marble cutter. 114 and 116, 136 and 138 Court Street
- Gallagher, John & Bro(s)., 1876, 1877, 1889
  Horses and carriages to let. Court Street, corner Schermerhorn St.; 73 and 75 South Elliott Place, and 71 Lafayette Avenue
- Gallagher, M., 1881
  Livery stables. 26 Verandah Place
- Galligan, M. Co., 1900
  Upholsterers and decorators. 164 Pierrepont Street
- Gannon & Hueston, 1877, 1881
  Plumbers, gas and steam fitters. 6 Hoyt Street cor. Fulton
- Ganzle, Geo., 1921
  Real estate. 179 Rutledge Street, near Lee Avenue
- Garcia, John, 1877
  Cigar importer. 111 Broadway, junction South 6th Street
- Garden Florist, Sam Takis, prop., 1933
  Florist. 198 Flatbush Avenue
- Gardiner Institute, 1880
- Gardner & Johnson, 1802
  Door Maker. 47 Carll Street and 66 Jay Street
- Gardner, Willis, 1883
  Plumber and gas fitter. 202 Division Ave. near Wilson St.
- Gargiulo, G., 1944
  Produce dealer. 2946 W. 22nd Street
- Garvey Brothers, 1880, 1883
  Plumbers, gas and steam fitters. 114 Court Street
- Gateson, E., 1865, 1867, 1868, 1869, 1872
  Plumber and gas fitter. 38 South Seventh Street; 38, 50 Broadway
- Gau, Louis, 1880, 1882
  Roofer. 254 Schermerhorn Street
- Gault & Grant / William J. Gault, 1884-1886, 1889, 1890
  Plumbers and gas fitters. 509 DeKalb Avenue bet. Franklin Ave. and Skillman St.
- Gaus, Charles H., 1891
  Grocer. 211 Meserole Street and 210 Bushwick Ave.
- Gay & Van Wicklen, 1865
  Carpenters and builders. 17 & 19 Third Street, bet. S. 8th & S. 9th
- Gaylor, W.H., 1867, 1875
  Carpenter, architect and builder. 113 Third Street; 110 South Eighth Street
- Gdynia-America Line, 1935
  Shipping and travel
- Geller, Andrew Shoe Manufacturing Co., Inc., 1940
  Shoe maker. 735 Lorimer Street
- General Repairing and Construction Co., 1897
  Construction. 396 & 398 Gates Avenue
- Genns, J., 1877, 1882, 1883, 1885
  Gas fitter, bell hanger, and locksmith. 504 Myrtle Avenue, corner of Ryerson Street
- Genung, M., 1871
  Undertaker. 370 Fulton Street
- Germain Metternich Post No. 122, G.A.R., 1898
  243 Floyd Street; 163 Bushwick Ave.
- German American Insurance Co., 1889
  24 Court Street
- German Commerical Institute, 1872
- Germania Fire Insurance Co., 1891
  G. Schimmel, Manager, Brooklyn Branch Office. 74 Court Street
- Gernshym, Henry & Bro., 1897
  32-50 Stockton Street
- Gerst, Henry P. & Son, 1883
  Carpenters and builders. 276 South Ninth Street
- Gfroerer & McCarty, 1889-1891
  Plumber, gas and steam fitter. 496, 660 Grand Street, near Ewen
- Gibbons, James & Thomas, 1863
  Masons and builders. 31 South 7th Street
- Gibbons, M. & Son, 1884
  Masons and builders. 55 Rapelyea Street
- Gibbs, F.W., 1883
  Lamps and oils. 80 Broadway corner 3rd St.
- Gibbs, John, 1887
  Painter and paper hanger. 874 DeKalb Avenue
- Gibson & Elsesser, 1879
  Machinists and blacksmiths. Foot of Court Street
- Gibson, Geo. C., 1867, 1870
  Grocer. 228 Court Street, cor. of Degraw
- Gies, Henry J., 1918
  Optometrist and optician. 1112 DeKalb Ave.
- Giesselmann, F.H., Dr., 1924
  Dentist. 984 Broadway
- Gilby, Geo. W., 1878
  Grocer. 22 and 24 Atlantic Market
- Gildersleeve, G.F., 1885
  Grocer. 925 Fulton St., near Clinton Ave.
- Giles, W. Thomas, 1880
  Heaters and house furnishings. 200 Franklin Street
- Gill, Baird & Co., 1883-1885
  Stone yard. Cor. Wythe Ave. and Keap St.
- Gill & Purdy, 1871, 1878
  Carpet warehouse. 257 Fulton Street, opp. Clinton St.
- Gill, Thomas Soap Co., Inc., 1890, 1902
  Soap maker. 711 Kent Avenue
- Gill, William (& Co.), 1897-1899
  Bell hanger and locksmith. 438 Sixth Avenue
- Gill, William, 1869
  Tin ware and metal roofer. 188 Myrtle Avenue, near Hudson
- Gilmour & Roche / George Gilmour, 1871, 1874
  Plumbers and gas fitters. 89, 99 Orange Street, near Fulton
- Gilroy, James J., 1903
  Boiler maker and sheet iron worker. Cor. 24th Street and 3rd Ave.
- Giordano, Francis L., 1959
  Lawyer. 26 Court Street
- Girl's Town of New York
  524 Tenth Street
- Gissel, Henry, 1883, 1885
  Tailor. 216 Broadway, cor. 7th Street
- Given Jr., Robert, 1881
  Carpenter. Tillary, cor. Canton Street
- Gladwish, F. H., 1884
  Coal dealer. Foot of Adams St.
- Glaser, J.M., 1892
  Painter. 88 Boerum St.
- Gleason, E.P. Manf'g. Co., 1896
  Glass works. 181 to 189 Mercer Street
- Gleason-Tiebout Glass Company, 1940
  Lighting glassware. 99 Commercial Street
- Gleichmann, William & Co., 1918
  Hay and feed dealers. 244 & 246 Howard Avenue
- Glick, D., 1903
  Metal worker
- Glidden, W.L., 1899
  Scaffolding and ladder dealer. 1035-1041 Atlantic Ave., bet. Franklin and Classon
- Glover, John R., 1874
  Lumber dealers. cor. Union St. & Gowanus Canal; Columbia cor. of Harrison St.
- Gobel, Adolf, Inc., 1927
  Butcher. Morgan & Flushing Aves. & Rock St.
- Godfrey, Edward J. & Son, 1871
  Marble manufacturer. Corner of Franklin and Noble Streets
- Goerlich, M., 1900-1901
  Upholsterer and decorator. Bedford Ave. (40 Locust St.)
- Goetz, C., 1880
  Furniture. 53 & 55 Moore Street
- Going, John, 1886
  Grocery. Cor. York and Adams Sts.
- Gokey, William (J.) & Son/Co., 1894, 1906
  Dry docks. Pier No. 1, Erie Basin
- Gold & Nicoll, 1900
  Stone contractor. First Street and Third Avenue
- Gold, Vining, Brown & Co., 1864
  Water heating company. 104 Fulton Street
- Goldberg, David, 1907
  City marshal. Pitkin cor. Stone Avenues
- Goldberg, M., 1944
  China and glass dealer. 2930 Stillwell Avenue
- Golden, I. & Bro., 1864
  Cooperage. 209 Second Street
- Goldsholle & Garfinkel, 1931
  Paint dealer. 977 Manhattan Ave.
- Goldsmith, B., 1878
  Hats, furs, and straw goods. 93 Myrtle Avenue
- Goldstein, A., 1933
  Heaters and plumbers' supplies. 372-374 Sutter Avenue
- Goodell, C.C., 1890
  Belt lacing and clamp agent. 178 Devoe Street
- Goodell, Geo. S., 1878
  Chemist. 1107 Fulton Ave.
- Goodman, Artie E.
  328 Troy Avenue
- Goodwin, M. & Co. / Goodwin, Cross & Co., 1877, 1882
  Lumber dealers. Classon, near Flushing Ave.
- Gordon, Bill Music Agency, 1950
  Music agency. 277 Graham Avenue
- Gorlitz, S., 1905
  Metal cornices and skylights. 64 Reid Ave., near Lafayette Avenue
- Gosden, Walter E.
  Village of Floral Park Historian. 197 Mayfair Avenue, Floral Park, NY
- Gottlieb Iron Works, Inc., 1952
  Iron work. 63 North Henry Street
- Gottlieb Weber & Co., 1914
  Furniture dealer [?]. 5, 7, and 9 LaGrange Street